Kyle Liu

(323) 206-1038 | kyleliu116@gmail.com | Los Angeles, CA github.com/kyle116 | kyleliu.info | linkedin.com/in/liukyle

SUMMARY

I am a web developer that works with programming languages such as HTML5, CSS3/Sass, JavaScript, and Ruby. I also make use of responsive design and SPA frameworks/libraries such as: React.js, Node.js, Express, Rails, jQuery, and Bootstrap. Before Web Development, I was a Valuation Analyst at a bank where I worked with large sets of data using SQL and Microsoft Excel, building models based on logic, inputs, and assumptions. Currently I am working on a volunteer team project called Project Light the Way to help veterans find helpful resources. This is part of the group Hack for LA where we use the MEAN(MongoDB, Express, Angular.js, Node.js) Stack.

SKILLS

Computer Languages:

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Ruby, Python

Databases:

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server

Other Technologies:

AWS, JSON Web Token, Heroku, JSX, Sass

SPA Frameworks & Libraries:

Rails, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap, jQuery, React.js, Angular.js

Version Control:

Git & Github

PROJECTS

Tender

- This app allows you to say yes and no to the pictures of food you like and matches you with the restaurant.
- Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, RESTful routes, Yelp API, Axios, and JWT

Business Card Exchange

- A digital contacts app to keep track of all contacts you meet. This app is a full CRUD app and follows the MVC pattern. The app uses PostgreSQL database and communicates with relational models.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, and Ruby on Rails

Bannd

- This app allows you to post stories about why you have been banned from an establishment.
- Technologies used: Node.js, Bootstrap, Express, AJAX requests, Yelp API, and MongoDB

Light the Way

- In 2020, the city of Los Angeles will have the highest population of veterans. This is an app that will provide information on where to find resources for veterans in the city of Los Angeles.
- Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, Angular.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, RESTful routes, and Grunt

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Assembly - Web Development Teaching Assistant, August 2017 - Present

Santa Monica, CA

- Provide teaching and mentorship to 20 students in each Web Development class in programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, Node.js, React.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Express, and Rails
- Lead TA sessions with help in class assignments, computer science topics, project building, and full stack development

CIT Group - Valuation Analyst, April 2016 - May 2017

Pasadena, CA

- Created models and analyzed the bank's assets and portfolios utilizing large loan data sets (10,000+ rows)
- Construction and execution of complex financial models for valuation of portfolios using Excel, MS SQL Server, Hyperion, BlackRock, Citrix, and Bloomberg

EDUCATION

California State Polytechnic Pomona - B.S. in Finance, September 2011 - December 2014 General Assembly, Santa Monica, CA - Web Development Immersive, May 2017 - August 2017